《纽约客》  你又来了
Oh, New Yorker, you've done it again.
杰  快来看这个漫画
Jay, check out this cartoon.
有会说话的狗吗
Does it have a talking dog?
-没  是在评价...  -我不看了
- No, it's a commentary on... - I'm out.
给你
Here you go,
我最用心做的一个
one of my best efforts.
吃吧
Have at it.
我不能吃
Mm, I can't eat that.
-为什么不能吃  -碰到酸黄瓜了
- Why not? - The pickle's touching it.
好了
There.
面包还是沾到汁了  好恶  那是什么
The juice got on the bread and, ew, what's that stuff?
香料
Spices.
跟海猴子似的
They look like sea monkeys.
你真的认真观察过酸黄瓜吗  杰
Have you ever really examine a jar of pickles, Jay?
黏糊糊的一团  我不吃了
It's like a swamp there. I'll pass.
出什么事了
What happened?
我给他做了个美味的三明治  他却不吃
I made him a beautiful sandwich and he won't eat it.
对啊  因为上面有腌黄瓜
Yeah, 'cause it had pickles on it.
乔在睡午觉
Joe is taking a nap.
我要去干洗店
I'm gonna go to the dry cleaners.
如果你路过寿司店
Well, if you're passing a sushi restaurant --
她不会路过的
She's not.
我从没听过谁不爱酸黄瓜的
I've never heard of anyone not liking pickles.
那今天就是历史性的一天啦
Aw, big day for you, then.
我自己做个烤奶酪三明治好了
I'm just gonna make myself a grilled cheese.
我应该是看到有格鲁耶尔奶酪了
I think I saw some Gruye in there.
我们有无花果吗
Do we have any fig?
坐下
Sit down.
你这种挑剔的毛病出去可不行
This whole persnickety thing is not gonna fly in the world.
别再给别人取笑你的理由了
Never hand people another reason to make fun of you.
你是指那些穿着皮夹克
You mean like all the cool kids
爱吃酸黄瓜的酷小孩吗
with their leather jackets and their pickles?
你至少尝一口酸黄瓜
Well, you're gonna sit there
否则坐在这儿不许走
until you at least try a pickle.
你被权力冲昏头脑了
You're drunk with power.
你说对了
You got that right.
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：亲爱的小饭  冰蓝  王大可  小花豆  Ethan-泽生  丁小七
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第二十二集
-不是吧  -怎么了
- Oh, no. - What?
托尼要来了
The Tonys are coming.
小卡  所以我才不希望你看那些
Cam, this is exactly why I don't want you watching them --
你已经这么生气了
You're already so angry.
不是托尼奖
Not that Tonys --
是安东尼・拉马克  肉毒杆菌托尼
Anthony Lamarque, botox Tony.
他们要来参加婚礼
They're coming to the wedding.
但说真的  又要上演《万事成空》吗
But, seriously, another revival of "Anything Goes"?
我们真的又要这样吗
Are we really doing this again?
他们要来我很惊讶
I'm surprised that they're coming,
因为我跟托尼提到婚礼时
because when I mentioned the wedding to Tony,
他表现出毫不在意的样子
he seemed completely disinterested --
是因为打了肉毒杆菌啊
Oh, the botox.
不
Oh, no.
还有你的表兄皮特  他的孩子们都要来
Your cousin Pete, all of his kids.
大家都接受了邀请  米奇尔
Everyone's accepting, Mitchell!
我爸的嘉宾名单还没给我呢
We haven't even gotten the list from my dad yet.
你爸的朋友们喝起酒来像当兵的
And your dad's friends drink like soldiers.
因为他们确实当过兵
Because they were soldiers.
我很感激他们为国奉献
I mean, I am grateful for their service,
但这样一来婚礼费用我们可承担不起了
but we are not gonna be able to afford this wedding.
看来我们得取消一些东西
Okay, maybe we need to pull back on a few things.
比如什么
Like what?
餐桌中心摆设
Uh, the centerpieces?
那你何必办婚礼呢
Why even have a wedding?
我不知道  小卡
I don't know, Cam.
因为我们彼此相爱  彼此尊重
Because we love and respect each other
还共同抚养一个孩子吗
and we're raising a child together?
你还要不要帮我了
Do you want to help or not?
也许我们可以发一些"不邀请信"
Maybe we could send un-vitations.
有这东西吗
Is that a thing?
因为我们现在可以结婚
We've already made a lot of people angry
已经惹怒很多人了
by just being able to get married.
就别把支持我们的人也疏远了
Let's not alienate the ones on our side.
好吧  也许我们可以卖掉些东西
All right. Maybe we could sell something.
已经超预算几千美元了
We're thousands over budget.
得卖个大件的才行
It would have to be something great.
给你  你可以把我的钻戒卖了
Here, you can sell my diamond ring.
亲爱的  那是糖果啦
Oh, honey, that's candy.
我要杀了那个杰克逊
I'm gonna kill that Jackson!
我确实有些贵玩意儿
I do have something of value --
一本《蜘蛛侠大战章鱼博士》漫画书
A "Spider-man versus doctor octopus" comic book.
1963年第3期  几乎全新
Issue number 3, 1963, near-mint condition.
值五千美元
It's worth 5 grand.
我9岁那年用一个橄榄球换的
I traded a football for it when I was 9 years old,
我爸气疯了
and my dad was mad
因为那上面有丹・马里诺的签名
because the football was signed by Dan Marino.
我说  找丽塔・莫雷诺签名我就留着
I said, "Get it signed by Rita Moreno, and I'll keep it."
不是吧
Oh, no.
我侄子们要从塔尔萨飞过来
My nephews are flying in from Tulsa
胖胖的那几个
-- the big ones.
特别能吃派的那些吗
The pie eaters?
没错  我得卖掉我的怀亚特・厄普了
That's it. I got to sell my Wyatt Earp.
这是怀亚特・厄普[西部警长]
This here is a belt buckle once worn
曾用过的皮带扣
by the great Wyatt Earp.
我爷爷在我7岁那年给我的
My grandpa gave it to me when I was 7 years old,
他说  孩子  这会保护你远离坏人
and he said,"Son, this will keep the bad guys away."
我20出头时  曾戴着它去参加
In my early 20s, I wore it to
牛仔和印第安人主题迪斯科派对
a Cowboys-and-Indians disco party.
但是没有起作用哦
And let's just say it didn't.
不行  我不会让你这样做的
No. I can't let you do that.
它对你意味着一切
That means the world to you.
小卡  我会卖了我的《蜘蛛侠》
Cam, I will sell my "Spider-man."
米奇尔  我的皮带扣曾是
Mitchell, my belt buckle was owned
老西部传奇人物的东西
by a legend of the old west.
我觉得你的漫画书卖的钱
I don't think your comic book
可能连买气球的钱都不够
would even cover our balloon budget.
这话就太刺...
Well, that's very offens--
等等  买气球要花多少钱
Wait. What's the balloon budget?
妈  能把这东西放到别的地方去吗
Hey, mom, can we put this stuff somewhere else?
它让我的房间显得好乱
It's cluttering up my room.
这是什么
What is it?
我的一些纪念品
Oh, just some mementos of mine.
还有你爸爸的
A few of your dad's.
-齐马  -是啊
- Oh, Zima! - Yeah.
齐马是什么
What's Zima?
酒瓶子里的派对
Just a party in a bottle.
那让我想起了狂野的时刻
Man, that reminds me of some wild times.
在我的土星车里放着比约克的歌
Cranking the Bjork in my Saturn
然后一起在影院看《西雅图夜未眠》时
before me and my buddies snuck some "Z"
呼呼大睡
into "Sleepless in Seattle."
真希望你也捂住了我的耳朵
I wish you'd covered my ears for that.
妈妈  抱着你的这个帅哥是谁啊
Ooh, mom. Who's this hottie with his arm around you?
帅爆了
Cute!
那是鲍比・纳什  我的前男友
Oh, that's Bobby Nash, my old boyfriend.
你为什么和他分手  为了爸爸吗
Why'd you break up with him? For dad?
这样说吧  他没盯住球
Let's just say he took his eye
结果被三振出局了
off the ball and struck out.
于是我站到了垒板上
So I stepped up to the plate
在票价低廉的座位上搞定了她
and nailed her in the cheap seats.
别那样说
Yeah, let's not say that.
我要走了
Well, I'm off.
亲爱的  我得去药店
Oh, honey, I've got to stop by the drug store.
你需要什么吗
Do you need anything?
不用  亲爱的
No, thank you, my dear.
邓菲腺体能分泌我需要的所有药物
The Dunphy glands produce all the drugs I need.
除了足部喷雾
Except for, uh, foot spray.
你能买一些来吗
Could you grab me some of that?
当然可以
Sure.
妈妈
Oh, wow, mom!
真是呆  对吧
What a dork, right?
你当时想些什么呢
What were you thinking?
但是很舒适  我爸爸不同意
It was comfortable. My dad didn't approve.
无须多言
Enough said.
我知道这难以置信
I know it's hard to believe,
但我过去其实有点呆
but I was actually a bit of a nerd back in the day.
我追克莱尔时  别人说我是癞蛤蟆
And it was suggested that I was out of my league
想吃天鹅肉
when I landed Claire.
大部分是杰说的
By Jay, mostly.
还有我的朋友们  还有我父母
And my friends. A-and my parents.
还有克莱尔
And Claire.
这是什么
What's this?
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
那是你爸爸大学里的答录机
That is your father's answering machine from college.
天啊  我有时忘了你们有多老
God, I sometimes forget how old you guys are.
你来到了菲尔的世界
You've reached Phil's world!
该狂欢了  太棒了
Party time! Excellent!
他真可爱
He's so cute.
菲尔  我是米奇尔
Hi, Phil. This is Mitchell,
普里契特  克莱尔的弟弟
uh, Pritchett, Claire's brother.
我就是想感谢你安排我和你表妹见面
I just wanted to thank you for setting me up with your cousin.
她人真好
She was very nice.
唯一的问题是  她住得有点远  所以
The only problem is she lives kinda far, so...
那是唯一的问题吗
That's the only problem?
邓菲狗  我是林
Hey, Dunph-dog, it's Ling.
带上你的旱冰鞋
Grab your rollerblades
在自行车道和我们见面吧  嗨起来
and meet us at the bike path, playa!
但我三点就得走了
But I got to be done by 3:00,
因为今天我要试飞新直升飞机
'cause today's the day I fly my new helicopter.
菲尔  我是克莱尔
Phil, hey, it's Claire. Um...
我得告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something,
我不想在电话里说
and I don't want to do it on your machine.
这事很重要
It's really important --
-不不不  -生死攸关
- Oh, no, no, no. - You know, life-and-death important.
给我  给我
Come on. Come on.
跟死无关  只是生[生命]
Not death, um, just life.
我是说... 我只是...  该死  我怀孕了
I mean... I just -- oh, hell, I'm pregnant!
甜蜜的新婚夫妇啊
Oh, sweet newlyweds!
别担心  你没必要娶我什么的
Don't worry. You don't have to marry me or anything.
我们尽快聊聊吧
Let's talk as soon as you can.
我们为什么不多加小心呢
Why weren't we more careful?
愚蠢的杜兰杜兰音乐会
Stupid Duran Duran concert.
好了
All right!
够了
That's enough.
我是在杜兰杜兰音乐会上被怀上的吗
I was conceived at a Duran Duran concert?
优雅人生的优雅开始啊
Classy start to a classy life.
你不是我在音乐会上怀上的
You were not conceived at the concert.
而是在音乐会后
It was after the concert.
什么  在车里吗
Oh, wha-- in the car?!
那是一辆好车
It was a very nice car.
我受够了  别再问了  我要走了
Listen, I am done. Stop snooping. I'm going.
车座靠背可以完全放平
The seats folded all the way back.
恶心的画面
Oh, images.
他们居然把"它"留下了
I can't believe they kept it.
我是有名字的
I have a name.
我是指答录机
The answering machine.
我们可以拿它找点乐子
You know, we could have some fun with this.
我回来了
I'm home!
妈妈
Hi, mom.
曼尼  你为什么坐在一根酸黄瓜面前
Manny, what are you doing sitting in front of a pickle?
杰说我得尝尝它的味道  否则就不许走
Jay says I can't leave until I taste it.
你为什么这样折磨他
Why do you torture him like this?
因为他太固执己见了  歌洛莉亚
'Cause he's too stuck in his ways, Gloria.
这对他有好处
This is good for him.
他会尝尝泡菜  发现自己喜欢吃
He'll taste the pickle, he'll find that he likes it,
然后尝试更多的东西
he'll try more things.
这是教子有方
This is good parenting.
在我的自传里  不会把这写成什么好事
This is not going to play well in my memoir.
你真会耍嘴皮子
You know, you're one to talk.
你跟你说过多少遍
How many times have I asked you
让你尝尝我妈做的猪血肠
to try my mother's blood sausages?
不是一回事  那香肠恶心死了
Totally different. That's disgusting.
你从来没吃过  怎么知道很恶心
How do you know it's disgusting if you've never tried it?
你从没尝过外婆做的美味的猪血肠吗
You've never tried grandma's delicious blood sausage
冰箱里就有啊
that's right there in the freezer?
你说得对
Oh, you're right.
我们确实还有些剩下的
We do have some left over.
是吗  还没有被哄抢着吃光吗
Really? It hasn't been all gobbled up yet?
好了  "年度最佳父亲"
Okay, Mr. Father of the year,
该向曼尼展示你不是个光说不做的人了
time for you to show Manny that you're not a hypocrite.
看来你陷入两难了
Looks like you're in quite a conundrum.
其实你可以说...
You know, you could've said --
"酸黄瓜"  该死  就摆在眼前
"A pickle"! Dang it! It was right there.
[in the pickle同指陷入两难]
你好
Hello.
你好  需要帮忙吗
Hi. Can I help you?
是的
Uh, yes.
我有一个很特殊的东西
Um, I have something pretty special
对我来说意义重大
that means the world to me,
但我愿意卖掉它
yet I gladly part with it
为了证明我对我未婚夫的爱
to prove my love for my fiance
-小卡  你不用  -我要这样做
- Cam, you don't have to... - I do.
这个皮带扣以前的主人是
This is a belt buckle that was once owned
传奇的怀亚特・厄普
by the legendary Wyatt Earp.
当我祖父把这个给我时  愿他安息
And when my grandfather gave it to me, and rest his soul,
他说  孩子  今年...
he said”son, this year is a
你还好吗
Are you ok?
我做不到  你来吧
I can't be here for this. You do it.
顺便再问问那盏灯卖多少钱
And get a price on that divine lamp.
不管怎么样
Um, anyway...
我不想当面打击
Look, I didn't want to say anything
你的未婚夫
in front of your fiance
但这只是个60年代时
but this is a cheap replica
加油站连锁店卖的廉价复制品
given away by a gas-station chain in the '60s.
市面上有一大堆
There's tons of them out there.
也就值20块
It's worth about 20 bucks.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
非常确定
Pretty sure.
他家的确喜欢夸张[打扮]故事
That family loves to dress up a story.
还有打扮小猪
And a pig.
那基本全新的初版第三期
Well, how about a first-edition number 3
《蜘蛛侠大战章鱼博士》能卖多少钱
"Spider-man versus doctor octopus" in near-mint condition?
继续说
Keep talking.
其实
That...
其实这就是全部了
Uh, uh, that's pretty much it.
她怎么还没打来
Why isn't she calling?
你总是对事情抱着怀疑态度
Aren't you the doubter?
她会打来  倒数三
She'll call in three...
二
two-o-o-o...
一  该数一了
One! One's next!
我知道
Yeah.
开始录音
Press record.
喂  妈妈
Hi, mom.
海莉  宝贝
Haley, honey,
你是想发这条短信给你爸爸吧
did you mean to send this text to your dad?
短信  什么短信
Text? What does it say?
"抱歉打扰你打高尔夫  但是..."
"I hate to spoil your golf game, but..."
不是  我没发那条短信
Uh, no, no. I-I didn't send that.
肯定是你和爸爸说话时
Must have accidentally dictated
手机不小心听写了
when you and dad were talking.
好吧  奇怪了
Okay. That's weird.
正好我打给你了
Well, while I have you on the phone,
你能把刷碗机里的餐具拿出来
would you mind emptying the dishwasher and doing --
你那边的信号弱了
Oh, you're breaking up.
海莉  能听见我说话吗
Haley, can you hear me now?
听不见了  再见
Nope. Bye.
-大功告成  -跟你说了没问题吧
- Got it. - Told you we'd get it.
只需创造性地剪辑一下
Now just for a little creative editing...
你那么聪明
Your mind is so brilliant.
如果你把这份聪明用到学习上的话
If you put this much effort into your schoolwork,
你一定能成就...
there is no telling the things you could --
你为什么总是那么扫兴
Why do you have to ruin everything?
是啊  她总是在说我的"潜力"
I know, she's always talking about my potential.
当心
Fore!
你觉得我打到她了吗
Do you think I hit her?
没有  她没事
Nah, she's fine.
对不起  我今天太分心了
Sorry I'm so distracted today.
怎么了  哥们
What's wrong, buddy?
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
你会不会有时候觉得
Do -- do you ever get the sense
你配不上你妻子
that your wife feels like she could have done better?
天呐  不会  她找到我算是三生有幸
God, no. Nah, she's the luckiest woman on earth.
非要说的话  是她配不上我
I mean, if anything, I could've done better.
那女人夜里发出的噪音
The noises that come out of that woman at night?
就好像她是《警察学校》里的那个黑人
It's like she's that black guy from "Police Academy."
说曹操  曹操就到
Oh, speak of the devil.
我老婆发来的信息
Message from my wife,
不是《警察学校》里的那个黑人
not the black guy from "Police Academy."
要真是他发的才给力呢
Oh, that'd be so awesome.
超给力的
That would be neat.
菲尔  我是克莱尔
Phil? Hey, it's Claire.
抱歉打扰你打高尔夫球  但是...
Um, I hate to spoil your golf game, but...
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant!
什么
What?
我们尽快谈谈吧
Let's talk as soon as you can.
我得走了
I have to leave.
什么  我们正在打比赛呢
What? We're in the middle of a game.
我得去找克莱尔
I have to be with Claire!
我的球杆
Oh -- my clubs!
我的帽子
My hat!
我的三明治
My sandwich!
对不起我在里面崩溃了
I'm sorry I freaked out in there.
我们卖了多少钱
How -- how much did we get for it?
给你  我做不到
You know, here. I couldn't do it.
什么  不是吧
What? No.
这个皮带扣对你来说意义重大
This belt buckle means so much to you.
我决定...还是把我的漫画卖了
I'm just gonna -- I am going to sell my comic book instead.
米奇尔  你真是太贴心了
Oh, Mitchell, that is so sweet. You know --
一想到我要跟我爷爷与怀亚特・厄普
The idea of me parting ways with a belt buckle
掰手腕赢来的皮带扣说再见
that my grandfather arm-wrestled Wyatt Earp for --
他掰手腕赢了他吗
He arm-wrestled him?
是啊  但不是为了争个胜负那种
Oh, yeah, but not in a contentious way.
要知道他们是朋友
You know, they were friends.
我爷爷在一次火车劫案里救了他
My grandfather saved his life during a train robbery.
火车劫案  太惊人了
A -- a train robbery? That's -- wow.
小卡  这太惊人了
Cam, wow!
他们关系很铁
They had a real bond.
伟大的怀亚特・厄普和诚实的亚伯・塔克
The great Wyatt Earp and honest Abe Tucker.
我心里知道  不拆穿
I have it, I'll store it,
必要时再拿出来说
and if I need to, I will use it.
这样吧  我放弃
You know what? I quit.
原谅我试图让他开眼界
Pardon me for trying to broaden his horizons.
不  不  你绝对不能放弃
No, no, no. You're not quitting anything.
你得把香肠吃了
You're going to eat your sausage,
而你得把你的酸黄瓜吃了
and you're going to eat your pickle.
我已经受够每天做两种饭了
I am tired of every day cooking two different meals.
不要番茄  只要白肉  多加培根
No tomatoes. White meat only. Extra bacon.
他能多吃培根  凭什么
He gets extra bacon? What the hell?
你们今天必须把这毛病改了
Today is the day you two are stopping this silliness!
我们今天都必须克服一些东西
Fine, we'll all conquer something today.
我有什么好克服的  我什么都吃
What do I have to conquer? I eat everything.
-抚摸斯黛拉的肚子  -什么
- Pet Stella's belly. - What?
你从来不摸斯黛拉的肚子
You won't touch Stella's belly.
因为感觉太奇怪了
Yeah, because it's the creepiest thing ever.
她有三十多个乳头
Has like 30 nipples.
我会把猪血肠吃掉
I'll eat the blood sausage,
曼尼会把酸黄瓜吃掉
Manny eats the pickles,
而你要抚摸她的肚子
you pet her belly.
我宁愿把狗吃了
I'd rather eat the dog.
别做个光说不练的人
Don't be a hypocrite.
要长长的爱抚  发自内心的
Nice and long, like you mean it.
我要看到她舒服得抖腿
I want to see that leg shake.
-我来拿吧  -发生什么事了
- Let me get these! - What's happening?
-我就是太高兴了  -真的吗
- I'm just so happy! - Really?
怎么  你一杆进洞了吗
Oh, did you finally get a hole in one?
一杆进洞
A hole in one.
我希望我们的宝宝也这么幽默
I hope our baby has your sense of humor.
-我们的什么  -我怎么没看出来呢
- Our what? - Why didn't I see it?
去药店  关节肿胀
The drug store, the bloated ankles,
你最近脾气也大了
you've been so moody lately...
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你看这暴脾气
There it is.
菲尔  我没怀孕
Phil, I am not pregnant.
-你没有吗  -没有
- You're not? - No.
那你怎么跟我留言说怀孕了
Well, why'd you leave me that message?
我没有给你留过言
Didn't leave you a message.
你确定吗  你怀孕时忘性特别大
Are you sure? You're very forgetful when you're pregnant.
我觉得我能记得住
I think I would remember!
那你为什么最近脾气这么大
Then why have you been so moody?
大概是因为你刚刚说我关节肿大
Maybe because you just told me I have giant ankles!
我不希望宝宝听到我们吵架
Shh, I don't want him to hear us fight like this.
把东西给我
Give me this.
这会对大家都有好处
Okay. This is gonna be good for everybody,
所以赶快行动吧
So let's get it over with.
-好吧  -好吧
- Fine. - Okay.
我们数三下
We'll go on the count of three.
一
One...
二
Two...
三
Three.
不
Uh! Oh, no!
我要吐了
I'm gonna throw up!
怎么这么湿  杰  为什么
Why so moist, Jay?! Why?!
我们来的时机不对吗
Is this a bad time?
很抱歉我们来得这么突然
Sorry to barge in here like this.
感觉挺奇怪我还把东西放在这里
I guess it's weird that, uh, I'm still storing stuff here.
我希望你来得再早一点
I just wish you would have come in sooner
在我跟斯黛拉上二垒之前
before I went to second base with Stella.
只需要两分钟
All right, I'll be two minutes.
如果你需要资金来筹备婚礼
If you need money for the wedding,
为什么要把心爱之物卖掉呢
why sell something that you love?
为什么不跟杰开口
Why don't you just ask Jay?
不  不  不  不
No. No. No. No.
为什么不  他是你爸
Why not? He's your father.
跟我爸爸开口要钱让我很不舒服
I don't feel right asking my dad for money, okay?
我成年了  而且我还有我的漫画书
I'm an adult, and I have my comic book.
抱歉打扰你打高尔夫  但是...
I hate to spoil your golf game, but...
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant!
我们尽快谈谈吧
Let's talk as soon as you can.
他们真厉害
Oh, they are good.
简直不敢相信他们能做得这么天衣无缝
I can't believe they pulled such an elaborate stunt.
我不知道是该生气还是该赞赏
I don't know whether to be angry or impressed.
简直太邪恶了
It's so diabolical.
不知道他们从哪里弄到的
I don't know where they get that...
等等  慢着
Wait. Wait. Wait.
我们可以好好捉弄一下他们
We could really have some fun with this.
说来好笑
You know, it's funny,
我从来不知道你喜欢漫画书
I never saw you as a comic-book guy.
我不喜欢  我也不知道
Oh, no, I wasn't, but I don't know.
《蜘蛛侠》
Spider-man --
让我产生了共鸣
He -- he spoke to me.
我觉得大概是因为这种
I -- I think it's because it's about this nerdy kid
一个小书呆子有着
who has this special secret side of himself
不可告人的另外一面的感觉
that he can't share with anybody, and --
我一直也都是这么觉得的
And that's how I always felt.
蜘蛛侠让我觉得与众不同没什么不好
Spider-man made me feel like it was okay to be different.
而且他让我在遇到困难时
And...it made me feel tough enough to --
变得足够坚强
to get through the rough times.
米奇尔  这真让人感动
Oh, Mitchell, that's so sweet.
我都不知道是这样的
I didn't know that.
你确定要把它卖了吗
Are you sure you want to sell it?
是的  确定
Yes, yes.
因为  就像蜘蛛侠一样  我勇敢坚强
Because, like Spider-man, I am brave and strong.
-蜘蛛网  蜘蛛网  -米奇尔
- Oh! Spider web! Spider web! - Mitchell.
弄到我嘴里了
It's in my mouth.
-米奇尔  -怎么了  天哪
- Oh, Mitchell! - What?! Oh!
不  不  不
No! No! Oh, no!
得了吧  菲尔
Give me a break, Phil!
你到底想我怎么样
What do you want from me?!
-小声点  -我什么都没说啊
- Shh! - I didn't say anything.
你听说我怀孕的时候
A little compassion when you thought I was pregnant
能不能多点热情
would have been nice!
对不起  那是我的下意识反应
I'm sorry. It was a knee-jerk reaction.
说你是个混蛋[jerk]倒是真的
You got that half right!
反正你也没怀孕  谁在乎呢
Well, you're not pregnant, anyway, so who cares?!
我说了什么你这么大火气
And what did I say that was so terrible?!
用你的原话说就是
Well, I believe your exact words were,
太好了  我们又有一个孩子可以糟蹋了
"Great, another kid that we could screw up.”
那对不起了  但我们都知道我说得没错
Oh, I'm sorry. But we both know that's true.
等等  你是说我们根本不应该要孩子吗
Wait. Are you saying we never should have them in the first place.
就好像你没这么说过一样
Like you never said that!
这太糟了
This is awful.
你一开始就知道会这样吗
This is what you thought gonna happen?
我想不到那么远的
I didn't think that far ahead.
从没想过  你知道的
I never do. You know that.
你应该阻止我的
You should've stopped me!
你说这会很有趣的
You said this was going to be fun!
现在没有人觉得有趣
Nobody is having fun!
说话注意点  菲尔
Careful?! Please, Phil!
如果你没有把我的肚子搞大
If you hadn't gotten me pregnant,
我根本不可能嫁给你
I never would have married you!
我肯定嫁给鲍比・纳什了
I would have married Bobby Nash!
-真的吗  -是啊
- You would?! - Oh, yeah!
现在我就该在阿斯本一百亩的大庄园里了
And right now, I would be on my 100-acre ranch in Aspen
和我两米多高做对冲基金的老公一起
with my strapping 6'4" hedge-fund husband!
你真的希望你嫁的是鲍比吗
You really wish you'd married Bobby?
每天都这么希望
Oh, every single day!
等等  菲尔
No, Phil.
爸爸  你还好吗
Dad, are you okay?
还行
Yep.
这家里每个人都这么看我
That's what I am to everyone around here.
-妈妈  -只是"还行"而已
- Mom... - Just "Okay."
-菲尔  -妈妈
- Phil! - Hey, mom?
-等会儿  -菲尔
- Not now. - Phil!
你们听见了吗  我们完全骗到他们了
You guys hear that? We totally got them!
快点  我们需要个吹风机
Quick! We need a blow dryer!
是有什么基佬紧急情况吗
Is this some sort of gay emergency?
不  爸爸  不是什么基佬紧急情况
No, dad, it's not a gay emergency!
是我的漫画书
It's my comic book.
我们要...  天呐
We need to -- ohh, god!
全毁了
It's ruined.
米奇尔  没事的
Mitchell, it's okay.
反正也许并不值那么多钱
It probably wasn't worth that much anyway.
这书值五千块  你的皮带扣分文不值
It was worth $5,000! Your belt buckle is garbage.
那是从加油站买的
It came from a gas station!
你祖父从来没见过怀亚特・厄普
Your grandfather never met Wyatt Earp!
这个秘密看来没有保守太久
I didn't hold on to that for quite as long as I thought.
对不起
Hey, I'm sorry.
这事我没想说的
I -- I didn't mean to blurt it out like that.
不  没关系
No, it's -- it's okay.
我也怀疑过时间点不太对
I -- I kinda suspected the dates didn't line up.
现在我开始怀疑那到底是不是
Now I'm starting to think that wasn't
阿梅莉亚・埃尔哈特的指南针了
Amelia Earhart's compass.
[阿梅莉亚: 著名美国女飞行员]
太可惜了  但我觉得杰肯定能帮到你们
I'm so sorry, but I am sure that Jay can help you two out.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
我们想自己解决这个问题
We want to do this on our own.
我能问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你们为什么要弄一个那么大的婚礼
Why are you having such a big thing anyway?
因为我们只结一次婚啊
Well, because we're only getting married once.
我只是想说为什么你们要如此大张旗鼓
I'm just saying, why do you need to make into a spectacle?
大张旗鼓
A s-- a spectacle?
这也许正是老天想要暗示你们
This could be the universe's way of telling you
把婚礼搞得低调一点
to bring it down a notch.
邀请家人  还有你们的朋友胡娇
Invite your family, your friend Pepper,
还有那个叫什么的  爱穿荷叶边的那个
and, what's his name, the -- the -- the flouncy one?
L・大卫
Uh, L'david.
我没有爱穿荷叶边的叫L・大卫的朋友
I don't have a flouncy friend named L'david, dad.
你是说L・迈克或是J・马库斯吗
Do -- do you mean L'michael or J'marcus?
我不太确定你说的是谁
I'm not sure who you're referring to.
管他呢
Whatever.
我就是说低调一点
I'm just saying keep it small.
为何要为了几乎不认识的人花那么多钱呢
Why pay all that money for people you barely know?
你是说你的那些朋友吗
Oh, oh, you mean like any of your friends?
拜托  你不会想邀请我的朋友们的
Oh, please, you don't want any of my friends there.
真的吗  因为我
Really? Because I've --
我管你要名单都要了几个月了
I've been asking for a list for months now.
到底是谁不想让他们来呢
So, so who doesn't want them there --
我还是你
me or you?
你为什么生气
Why are you getting upset?
因为如果这是克莱尔的婚礼
Because, dad, if -- if this was Claire's wedding,
你就会投入得多了
you would be all over it.
你甚至会要求在你的俱乐部办
You'd be wanting to have it at your club.
你会邀请你所有的朋友
You'd be inviting all your friends.
拜托
Oh, please!
克莱尔结婚时我也一样不那么兴奋
I wasn't that thrilled when Claire got married, either.
"也一样"  老天爷啊  别说了
"Either"? For god's sake, just stop talking.
所有人都退一步
Everybody back off.
我不觉得我说得过分
I don't think I'm out of line
我的朋友不会想在盛大的
suggesting my friends don't want to see
同志婚礼上  看父子共舞
a father-son dance at a big gay wedding.
根本没什么父子舞  老爸
There is no father-son dance, dad.
我不知道在同志婚礼上是什么情况
I don't know what things go on there.
我需要牵着你走红毯吗
Do I walk you down the aisle?
会有人扔花束吗
Does someone throw a bouquet?
我是说  我不知道
I mean, I'm just saying, I don't know
如果我俱乐部那些朋友来了
how this stuff plays out
会是怎样的情况
with my guys from the club.
你是说那些围坐在屋子里
Oh, you mean the guys who sit around the locker room
裸身看橄榄球赛的人吗
watching football naked?
不  别劝我  问题不在于他们
No! No! See, this -- this isn't about them.
而在于你
This is about you.
是你觉得有点不太能接受
You are the one that's uncomfortable here.
好吧  我承认
Fine. I admit it.
你们的整个婚礼在我看来都很古怪
This whole wedding thing is weird to me.
为什么你可以做真实的自己
Now, see, why do you get to be you,
而我却不可以呢
but I don't get to be me?
我也不想对此感到不太能接受
See, I didn't choose to be uncomfortable.
《Born this way》是Lady Gaga的著名撑同性恋歌曲
深受广大同性恋的喜爱
但我生来就是这样的人
I was born this way.
你现在真的要用同志圣歌来堵我们的嘴吗
Are you really throwing a gay anthem in our face right now?
该死的  你也理解一下我吧
Oh, damn it. Give me some credit.
你知道我做到今天这样有多不容易
You know how far I've come.
你还希望我怎么样呢
I mean, what more do you want from me?
算了  老爸  你可以的
You know what, dad? Y-you do.
你也可以做真实的自己
You do get to be you.
如果你真的不太能完全接受的话  那么
If -- if it really makes you that uncomfortable, then...
就别来参加我们的婚礼了
don't come to the wedding.
米奇尔
Mitchell...
别  瞧  我们已经在削减参与人员了
No! No, see? We're scaling back already.
菲尔  亲爱的
Phil, honey...
刚刚在下面是怎么回事
What happened down there?
你攻击了我
You attacked me.
那是在玩啊  我们都在互相攻击啊
In a fun way. We were both doing it.
我听到你今早说的话了
I heard you this morning,
谈论你超帅的男友鲍比
Talking about your super-cute boyfriend Bobby,
说我只是个"舒适的"选择
saying that I was the "Comfortable" choice,
你跟我结婚只是为了跟你爸作对
that you only married me because your dad hated it.
不  亲爱的
No, sweetheart.
我当时不是在说你
I was not talking about you.
我是在跟女儿们解释
I was explaining to the girls
我有张照片上穿的那身衣服
about an outfit that I was wearing in a picture
是个"舒适的"选择
that was the comfortable choice
而我爸很讨厌这件衣服
that my dad hated.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
你怎会以为我是因为那样才跟你结婚的呢
You can't possibly think that's why I married you.
好吧  我懂你爸这人
Okay, I -- I get it a-about your dad.
但有时候我真的会假想
I -- I -- sometimes I do wonder, you know,
如果你当时没怀孕
if you hadn't gotten pregnant...
-我们会像现在这样在一起吗  -是啊
- would we even be here right now? - Yeah.
我也老是想同样的问题
Well, I wonder the same thing, too.
是吗
You do?
是啊  经常想
Yes. All the time.
就上周
Just last week,
你和孩子们在外面洗车
you and the kids were outside washing the car,
你们开始了肥皂泡大战
and you got in that soap battle
大家都在跑  不停地笑
and everybody was running around laughing.
我站在厨房的窗前
And I stood there at the kitchen window,
心想着我是多么幸运
and I was thinking how lucky I am.
因为如果我没跟你结婚的话
'cause I would have missed all of this
就会错过这一切
if I hadn't married you.
我知道你在看
I knew you were watching.
所以我故意把海绵掉在了地上
That's why I dropped the sponge.
正是这个动作最开始吸引了我的注意力
That's what got my attention in the first place.
你真的不后悔没嫁给鲍比・纳什吗
You really don't regret not marrying Bobby Nash?
不后悔
No.
他是很帅  但也很无趣
He was cute, but he was boring.
他都没成功逗笑过我一次
He never once made me laugh.
我经常能逗得你笑
You laugh at me all the time.
是啊
I do.
我很喜欢你听说我怀孕时
I liked how happy you were
表现出的那种喜悦
when you thought I was pregnant.
那是当然了
Of course I was.
你可以帮我捡起来吗
Do you think you could pick that up for me?
不知道呢
I don't know.
真的好低哦
It's so far down here.
瞧吧  我就说他们肯定会和好的
See? I told you they were gonna be fine.
-锁门了  -快跑
- Door lock! - Run!
快走  快走
Go! Go! Go! Go!
嗨菲尔  我是米奇尔  克莱尔的弟弟
Hey, Phil, it's Mitchell, Claire's brother.
我听说你把克莱尔搞怀孕了
I heard about your and Claire's whole pregnancy situation,
我很抱歉我爸的反应那么恶劣
And I'm -- I'm sorry my dad didn't have a better reaction.
你别往心里去
Don't take it personally.
他就是那样的人
He's just like that.
他会想通的
He'll -- he'll come around.
如果他想不通的话
And if not...
那也是他的损失
His loss.
对了  总之
Yeah, okay, anyway,
既然我们已经是一家人了
uh, now that we're gonna be family,
我如果和你表妹谈恋爱的话可能有点怪
it's -- it's probably a little weird for me to date your cousin,
或许你可以让她别再呼我了
so maybe you could ask her to stop paging me?
真是太疯狂了
It's so crazy.
我也觉得  戴着呼机的米奇尔舅舅
I know. Uncle Mitchell with a pager.
不行  斯黛拉  别妄想了
No, Stella. Okay? No!
斯黛拉  我说了不行
Stella, I said no.
你...
You...
好吧  就这一次
Okay, but just this time, okay?
你最好死守这个秘密
And you keep your mouth shut about this.
是谁鬼鬼祟祟的
Who's there?